There are many monsters threatening humans.
有许多怪物 威胁着人类
Many brave adventurers stepped forward bravely.
挺身而出的是 众多勇敢的冒险家
And I,
而我
Alvin, is one of them.
埃尔文就是其中一位
Forming a party with the healer Carla,
与僧侣卡菈组队
let's continue the adventure today.
今天也持续冒险旅程
DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER
(这个僧侣有够烦)
THE TITLE "THE SECOND HALF OF THIS EPISODE FINALLY GETS TO THE CONTENT OF "WHAT'S THIS STORY"."
(此次的标题) (这集后半段终于进入"这是什么故事"的内容了)
"(STILL, BUT ONLY THIS TIME AND NEXT TIME.)" Excuse me.
((话虽如此但也只有这次和下次两次而已)) 不好意思
"I'LL EXPLAIN IT AGAIN IN CASE SOMEONE DOESN'T KNOW." Yes.
(怕有人不知道所以再说明一次) 是
""WHAT'S THIS STORY" IS THE STORY BEFORE THIS STORY BECAME "DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER"." Welcome to Adventurer Guild.
("这是什么故事"是本故事变成"这个僧侣有点烦"之前) 欢迎来到冒险家公会
THAT'S THE STORY POSTED ON THE ONLINE SUBMISSION WEBSITE BEFORE SERIALIZATION. ALTHOUGH IT HASN'T BEEN INCLUDED
(也就是在连载之前放在网络投稿网站的故事) (所以虽然还没收录在漫画中)
"IN THE COMIC, YOU MAY READ IT ON THE INTERNET. PLEASE READ IT ONLINE IF YOU WANT." Hi, Mr. Alvin.
(但应该还能在网络上看得到 想看的话请上网看) 你好 埃尔文先生
"BUT THERE'S A WICKED CHARACTER IN THE FIRST HALF THAT YOU CAN'T MISS." It's been a while.
(不过前半段有位绝不能错过的可恨角色登场) 好久不见了
"THE REASON WHY YOU SHOULD PAY ATTENTION IS..." Miss Carla, you're looking well, too.
(之所以请大家务必注意的原因是) 卡菈小姐也看起来很有精神
YOU'LL KNOW IF YOU CONTINUE TO WATCH IT. IN SHORT, THERE ARE MANY CONTENTS IN EPISODE TEN.
(今后继续看下去就懂了) (总之有许多内容的第十话)
What are you waiting for? Say hello.
磨蹭什么 快打招呼
Please don't talk to me casually...
请不要随便跟我搭话…
All right. Stop it.
好 别说了
Sorry, our goblin is rude.
抱歉 我家哥布林很没礼貌
Not at all. Both of you are interesting as ever.
不会 两位还是这么有趣
Why are you coming to our guild today?
今天 来本公会有何事呢
I'm here today to update the ranking of adventurers.
我今天是来更新冒险家排行的
To update the ranking of adventurers, right?
更新冒险家排行是吗
You're thinking, "Do you think you can rank up" and "bracket laugh", right? How rude.
你正在想"你以为能提升排行吗" "括号笑"对不对 真没礼貌
That's what you think.
那是你的想法吧
I thought, "do you want to make the ranking worse"
我想的是 "你还想让排行变的更糟吗"
and "bracket laugh".
"括号笑" 才对
It's totally different.
完全不一样
Keep murmurs in your mind.
murmur给我放在心里
So it's the paper to test the ranking. Blood will be collected for judgement.
那么 这是检测排行的纸张 我们采用采血判断
The magic array will make a ranking judgement from one star to five stars based on actual achievement and experience.
上面的魔法阵 会根据实绩和经验 来做一星到五星的排行判断
Collect blood for judgement. Are you okay with it, Mr. Alvin?
要采血判断哦 埃尔文先生没问题吗
Just a little cut on the finger.
只是稍微在手指上弄个小伤口
There's nothing to worry about.
有什么好担心的
I'm afraid you'll be "scared to death".
我担心你会"吓死"
I won't, okay?
才不会好吗
Do you want me to help you make a mistake?
要帮你介错吗
You should help me recover.
应该是帮我恢复吧
Mr. Alvin, how many stars is your current ranking?
埃尔文先生现在的排行是几星
I'm sorry. It must be one star...
对不起 肯定是一星…
Zero.
零
The magic array didn't respond at all last time.
上次 魔法阵毫无反应
So my ranking is zero star.
所以我的排行是 零星
It's ridiculous, right?
很好笑吧
Sorry, I never thought there was a worse ranking.
对不起 我从没想过 还有更惨的排行
How many stars is Carla's ranking?
卡菈的排行是几星
It's... three stars.
是… 三颗星
Oh, yeah...
是哦…
It must have been impossible to judge when you last updated it on a cloudy day.
埃尔文先生上次更新时 一定是因为阴天无法判断吧
You can't see stars on cloudy days. I'm just kidding.
阴天看不到星星 开玩笑的啦
It's like my life that can't see what's ahead.
跟我那看不到前方的人生一样
-It's not funny... -It's so funny.
-好难笑… -好好笑
I think... There must be something wrong with the paper tested.
我想…一定是检测的纸张有问题
Yeah, you're just unlucky.
没错 你只是运气不好啦
But I did it five times...
但我做了五次…
Those five pieces of paper are all defective.
那五张纸都是瑕疵品啦
Mr. Alvin, you're so unlucky.
埃尔文先生 你的运气真差
But the worst is the ranking, right?
不过差的是排行 对吧
Mr. Alvin, I was joking.
埃尔文先生 我开玩笑的啦
I just wanted to lighten the atmosphere.
我只是想缓和气氛
Please calm down. The test has nothing to do with blood volume.
请冷静 检测与血量无关
Please don't give up on yourself.
请不要自暴自弃
Even if you don't sacrifice that arm, there will be a star this time.
就算不牺牲那条手臂 这次一定会有星星的
We met golem, Cyclops,
一路上遇到了魔像 独眼巨人
necromancer and Medusa along the way.
死灵法师 还有梅杜莎
We met so many monsters, and you survived.
遇到这么多魔物你都活下来了
Is it true?
这是真的吗
You fought with so many ferocious monsters, yet you survived...
你跟这么多凶狠的魔物战斗 仍活了下来…
Yeah, that's right...
是这样没错啦…
There will be a star this time. No, at least four stars.
那这次一定会有一星 不 至少有四星的
Really?
真的吗
Great. Rise to the top adventurer at one go.
太好了 一口气升到上级冒险家
No, it's not sure yet.
不不不 又还没确定
But it makes sense. I have the experience that common adventurers don't have.
但有道理 我有普通冒险家 都没有的经验
I even think I've been trying hard.
连我都觉得自己很努力了
Stop bragging. Just test it.
别自吹自擂了 快点测吧
Don't hurry.
别急别急
Having two stars is also nice, though.
差不多有个两星也不错
How many stars are there?
究竟有几颗星呢
Look, Mr. Alvin.
看 埃尔文先生
There's a response on the paper.
纸张有反应了
There must be at least one star.
确定至少有一颗星
(LAUGH)
(笑)
Bracket laugh.
括号 笑
I said it has nothing to do with blood volume.
就说了跟血量无关
There must be another way to stop me.
应该有别的方法能阻止我吧
I wonder why it's so noisy. It's you, Alvin.
我还想说怎么这么吵 原来是埃尔文啊
Amazing. You're still alive.
真惊人 你还活着啊
I thought you were killed by a stray dog.
我以为你早就被野狗咬死了
Do you know him?
你认识他吗
Kind of.
算认识吧
He's an adventurer like us.
他跟我们一样是冒险家
Like you? How ridiculous!
跟你一样 笑死人了
Don't compare me to the lowest ranking newbie.
别把我跟最低等的杂鱼相提并论
What are you talking about?
你说什么
Leave him alone. It was just a boring provocation.
别理他 那只是无聊的挑拨
You just said Mr. Alvin
你刚才说埃尔文先生是
is a newbie, slug, shameless stray dog, extra and old man, right?
臭杂鱼蛞蝓不要脸丧家之犬 杂角大叔对不对
How mean.
太可恶了
He didn't say so!
人家没说
Who's this who looks like a fugitive?
这位看起来像逃犯的人是谁
A fugitive?
逃犯
Interesting kid, tell me your name.
有趣的小鬼 报上名来
Have you ever heard that you should introduce yourself first before asking someone's name?
你听过问别人名字时 要先自我介绍的说法吗
You can't say that because you're a fugitive, right?
因为你是逃犯 所以不能说对吧
You little brat.
臭小鬼
Calm down, Brigan.
布利迦冷静
She bears no ill will.
她没有恶意
She just doesn't filter her speech.
只是没带言语过滤功能
-Brigan. I see. -Our goblin is really rude.
-布利迦 原来如此 -我家的哥布林真的很没礼貌
So that's your name.
那就是你的名字啊
You have a nice name.
名字挺不错的嘛
Look. She's telling the truth.
看 这也是她的真心话
Prison. What a nice name for a fugitive.
监狱的英文就是Prison 很适合逃犯的名字
Don't say it.
不要说出来
Wicked dark elf, are you...
可恶的黑妖精 你是不是…
A dark elf dressed as a healer?
打扮成僧侣的黑妖精
And the words that make one angry.
还有令人火大的用词
Are you Carla, by any chance?
你该不会是卡菈吧
Right.
没错
"Goddess sent from Heaven", Carla, it's me.
"天降女神"卡菈 就是我
You should have just fallen under the ground.
你干脆直接降落到地底下算了
You haven't formed a party, have you?
你们该不会组队了吧
A lot of things... happened.
发生了…许多是嘛
The party of the notorious "Calamity Mine Carla"
恶名昭彰的"灾祸地雷卡菈"
and "Walking Luggage" Alvin.
和"行走行李"埃尔文的队伍
What a masterpiece.
简直是杰作啊
Geez. He said it so badly. Can you stand hearing that, Mr. Alvin?
可恶 他说得这么难听 埃尔文先生不会不甘心吗
But he was telling the truth.
不过 他说的是事实啊
I was called Calamity Mine Carla. Can you stand it?
我被说成灾祸地雷卡菈 你不会不甘心吗
Oh, it's nothing.
哦 我无感
I can't stand it.
我很不甘心
Why would Mr. Alvin be a walking luggage?
埃尔文先生 怎么会是行走行李
Carla...
卡菈…
Not only you can walk, but you can also talk.
明明不只会行走 还会说话耶
You'd better shut up.
你可以闭嘴了
I was complimenting you.
我可是在夸奖你们耶
A troublesome guy and a burden.
麻烦的家伙和拖油瓶
Best partner.
简直是绝配
We're not the best partner, right?
哪有 什么绝配啊 对吧
It's slandering.
简直是污蔑
How about the name of our party called "waste bin"?
合在一起队名就叫"废弃箱"如何
It's disgusting. Why are you so happy?
太令人厌恶了 你为什么这么开心
Waste bin. That's a good name.
废弃箱 这个名字不错
You're so talented.
你好有才哦
I am, right?
对吧对吧
And Mr. Brigan is perfect for prison.
而布利迦先生 很适合进监狱
You little brat!
臭小鬼
He suddenly got angry. His EQ is so low.
他突然发飙了 EQ好低哦
It's not suddenly.
才不是突然
Instead, I think he has endured it for a long time.
我反而觉得他忍很久了
How dare you look down on me.
竟敢瞧不起我
You won't know how great I am if I don't teach you a lesson.
不给你一点教训 就不知道老子的厉害
Alvin! Give her to me...
埃尔文 把她交给我…
I refuse.
我拒绝
You just mocked me. Do you think I'm easy as I don't say anything?
刚才被你嘲讽一般 我不吭声你就把我当病猫啊
Mr. Alvin.
埃尔文先生
Do you want to fight? How bold of you.
要打吗 有种
Let's fight outside.
到外面打吧
What now?
怎么办
As I wish, I'm ambitious, too.
如我所愿 我也是有志气的
But I might get beaten badly.
不过 我可能会被打得很惨
Please help me recover later.
之后拜托你帮我恢复了
Got it.
我知道了
What's wrong? You don't dare fight outside? You wimp.
怎么了 不敢到外面打吗 软脚虾
Shut up. Wash your neck and wait.
吵死了 你给我洗好脖子等着
Don't run away.
别逃哦
Impossible!
怎么可能
Take advantage!
有机可乘
Brigan.
布利迦
What did you do?
你干什么啊
I saw such an unguarded back.
我看到这么没有戒心的背部
Without a second thought...
想都没想就…
"LEGENDARY WRESTLER, KILLER NUMBER TWO" Your occupation is an assassin...
(传说中的摔角选手 杀手2号) 你的职业是杀手…
"SELF SATISFIED SKILL, VIOLATION ATTACK, ALL SKILLS" Not this!
(得意技能 违规攻击 全体技) 不是这个
"KILLER, SELF SATISFIED SKILL, SURPRISE ATTACK, ALL SKILLS" Yes, that's it.
(杀手 得意技能 奇袭攻击 全体技) 对 就是这个
Great. You're still alive.
太好了 你还活着
What happened...
发生什么事了…
Well... I'm sorry.
那个…抱歉
No. Heal him first.
不 还是先帮他疗伤吧
Just leave it to me.
交给我吧
Why do you tie him up?
为什么绑他
Nice. Got him.
好 抓到了
He's not a fugitive.
他不是逃犯啦
It's the legendary mansion.
这里就是传说中的馆邸
Right.
对
The cannibal hall occupied by the resentful ghost.
被怨灵占据的食人馆
It seems that the ghost has to be eliminated here.
看来此地非除灵不可了
We broke the table when we fought with Brigan.
跟布利迦起争执时 我们弄坏了桌子
We were punished for causing trouble to the guild.
给公会带来了困扰 而受到了责罚
It looks like an ordinary ruin,
看起来只是普通的废墟
but it brings a terrifying atmosphere.
但确实感觉到恐怖的气氛
I heard it's also called "amazing, frightening horror house".
听说又称 "惊人 吓人 惊悚屋"
It has the vibe of a "leisure facility".
好有"休闲设施"的气氛啊
But it's said that none of the people who entered the mansion can come back alive.
但听说进入这座馆邸的人 没有一个人能活着回来
I think they were killed by the resentful ghost staying in the mansion.
我想应该是 被栖息在馆邸的怨灵杀死了
Here it appears. Settings that often arise in the horror house.
出现了 惊悚屋常出现的设定
Whatever you think. I'll leave off the rest.
要怎么想随便你啦 以下省略
You don't believe?
你不相信哦
Who would believe that?
这种事谁会相信啊
It happened suddenly. We have a witness today.
事出突然 今天我们请到一位证人
I invited someone who actually entered the mansion.
我请了一位实际进入这座馆邸的人
No, it's supposed that no one will come back alive.
不行啦 设定是没人能活着回来
Witness, please.
有请证人
Hello, everyone.
大家好
The ghost appeared.
幽灵出现了
This is Miss Anna, the former thief
这位是实际进入馆邸
killed by the resentful ghost
过没多久就被怨灵杀死的
shortly after entering the mansion.
前盗贼安娜小姐
A round of applause.
拍手
Carla, no. It's embarrassing.
卡菈 不要啦 好丢脸哦
No. I've got to introduce you.
不行 得好好介绍你啊
But you said, "killed shortly after". Doesn't that mean I'm a bad thief?
可是你说"过没多久就被杀死" 不就代表我这个盗贼很差吗
But you're really dead.
不过 你真的死了啊
No, that resentful ghost was terrible.
不是啦 那个怨灵真的很糟啦
"GET RIGHT TO FT" What's that guy doing?
(直接进入FT) 那家伙在干嘛
Hold on. You were here!
等等 原来你在啊
Where have you been?
之前都上哪去了
I helped Sister Carla find the crystal ball. Then I got lost.
我帮卡菈大姐找水晶球 然后就迷路了
It was over.
那件事已经结束了
Really...
真假…
Let's not stand here. Go inside and talk.
我们别站在这说 到里面聊吧
It's freezing today, after all.
毕竟今天很冷
Do ghosts feel cold?
幽灵会觉得冷吗
Wait, wait, wait!
慢着慢着慢着
What's the matter? We're going to enter the mansion and throw dice with written themes.
什么事 接下来要进入馆邸 丢写好主题的骰子
Then follow the topic and chat...
然后沿着主题接到闲聊…
Heart-pounding conversation...
心跳加速的动心谈话…
How annoying!
烦死了
Do you want to join the girls' talk?
你想加入女孩们的闲聊吗
Can a 30-year-old man keep up?
30岁的男人跟的上吗
Why do you know my ag... No.
为什么知道我的年… 不对
This mansion is dangerous, right?
这座馆邸很危险吧
Why do we just go in?
为什么随随便便就进去了
You should ask her more and be prepared.
你应该多问问她 然后做好防备
Are you...
难道你…
No way.
不会吧
What? I'm not afraid...
干嘛 我才不怕…
Speak properly!
好好说话
First of all, I'm really not afraid.
先说好 我真的不怕
It's okay. Everyone is bad at something.
没关系 谁都有不擅长的事
What's more, the resentful ghost is related to "death".
更何况怨灵 与"死亡"有关
It's normal for a living person to fear "death".
活人恐惧"死亡" 是很正常的
I said that's not it!
就说了不是
All right. Here's the problem.
好 问题来了
The natural enemy who's called a resentful ghost receives divine protection.
人称怨灵的天敌 受到神圣加护
They look so pitiful that people want to protect them.
看上去楚楚可怜 令人想好好保护
Who's the beautiful cleric with silver hair and brown skin?
银发 褐色皮肤 美丽动人的圣职人员是谁
Correct.
答对了
What are you trying to say?
你到底想说什么
All right. I've got the strategy for dealing with resentful ghost.
好 对付怨灵的策略已经想好了
Let's go and solve the task.
三两下去解决任务吧
What's wrong? What makes you uneasy?
怎么了 还有什么好不安的
It's you who makes me feel the most uneasy.
就是你让我感到最不安
Don't worry. I'm protected by the divine.
放心吧 有受到神圣加护的我在啊
Maybe it's plausible.
搞不好 对方是个能说得通的对象
Even if I can't persuade it, I'll use the iron fist of fraternity to make it obedient.
就算劝不了 我也会用博爱铁拳 让对方听话的
Is iron fist even a fraternity...
铁拳到底哪里博爱了…
Welcome ba...
欢迎回…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Sorry, I'm a useless healer.
对不起对不起 我是个派不上用场的僧侣对不起
I appreciate you form a party with me,
我真的很感谢你跟我组队
but I also feel guilty.
但同时我也觉得很有罪恶感
Oh, no. She's talking nonsense out of fear.
糟糕 她因为恐惧而胡言乱语了
Someone like me who's mischievous and useless
像我这样人小鬼大 又派不上用场的人
should stay at home and live gloomily.
就应该关在家里不要出门 过着阴郁的生活才对
Don't say so!
别这么说
Don't worry. I forgive you for everything so far.
放心 至今的事我都原谅你
So please keep it that way, Carla.
所以 卡菈就继续保持现在的状态
Please!
拜托
SINCERE
(真切)
You're so generous.
你真是心胸宽大的人
You're gentle and tolerant.
包容一切的温柔
Just...
简直…
Just like me.
就像我
Geez. She recovered.
可恶 她恢复了
I was too careless.
我太大意了
I didn't expect it to be so exciting at first.
没想到一开始就这么刺激
Yeah.
就是啊
The resentment is so strong that even I'm affected.
怨念强到连我都受到影响
It seems that it's hard to deal with.
看样子对手不简单啊
And...
而且…
Someone sacrificed again because I was caught off guard.
因为我的措手不及而又有人牺牲了
Things are getting more and more troublesome.
事情变得越来越麻烦了
Isn't resurrection magic useful to the resentful ghost?
复活魔法对那个怨灵没用吗
A newbie who doesn't know magic is a pain in the neck.
不懂魔法的新手真令人头痛
Resurrection magic is super difficult magic.
复活魔法是超高难度魔法
It's not magic that can be used whenever and wherever.
不是随时随地能使用的魔法
I can do it, though.
虽然 我会就是了
You can do it?
你会啊
But I'm not proficient at it.
但是我还不熟练
It can bring someone back to life who's just died for three seconds.
要刚死亡三秒钟的人 才能让他复活
Three seconds...
三秒…
But at least she can do it.
但至少她会
However,
不过
the chant required for resurrection magic
复活魔法所需咏唱的魔法
will take ten seconds.
得花 10秒
You can't make it!
来不及啊
If I guess correctly that "this person will die", I can chant early.
若猜中"这人会死" 提早咏唱就没问题
You should do something to prevent people from dying.
应该做避免人家死掉的事吧
Forget it. Let's go back.
算了 我们回去吧
Could you please wait a minute?
能稍等一下吗
What?
干嘛
The resentful ghost seemed to say something.
刚才那只怨灵好像说了什么
He said "welcome back".
他说了"欢迎回来"
That's right.
没错
So what?
那又怎样
How should I put it?
怎么说呢
We met for the first time. It's shameless to say so.
我们是初次见面 这样说很厚脸皮
You really are...
你真的是…
I'm supposed to be the natural enemy of the resentful ghost.
照理说 我是怨灵的天敌
But he said to me, "welcome back, star." He must be looking down on me.
他却对我说"欢迎回来 星星" 绝对是瞧不起我
He's not that friendly.
他没这么友善吧
Anyway, the resentful ghost made me feel frustrated for the first time.
总之那只怨灵 让我初次感到挫败
I'm a woman who'll take an eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth.
我是以牙还牙以眼还眼的女人
I'll make that resentful ghost wear cat ears and dress as a maid.
我要让那只怨灵 戴猫耳穿女仆装
And say, "welcome back, meow, star."
然后说"欢迎回来喵 星星"
What an unnecessary counterattack.
超没必要的反击
Don't worry. I won't mess around.
放心吧 我不会乱来的
I'll let it wear cat ears and dress as a maid.
只会给他戴猫耳穿女仆装
I don't understand why we're here.
我已经搞不懂我们来这里的目的了
Excuse me, Zanko!
打扰了山靠
How you open the door!
开门的方式
Come out.
出来吧
Let me teach you the etiquette of greeting someone you meet for the first time.
让我教教你跟初次见面的人 打招呼的礼仪
How boastful of someone who doesn't know how to open the door.
不懂开门方法的人 竟然如此大言不惭
You... You come out.
你你你出来啦
You just made me embarrassed.
刚才就是你害我丢脸
But it's not going to be easy this time.
但这次可就没饿么见单了
Open your eyes. Don't face me.
张开眼睛 不要面对我
-Carla! -Wh... What's wrong? Are you trying to scare me?
-卡菈 -什什什么事 想吓我吗
Look behind you.
快看后面
I won't be scared anymore.
我不会再被吓到了
But don't scare me from behind...
但不可以从后面吓…
Welcome back, meow!
欢迎回来喵
What a mess.
乱七八糟
Not... Not bad.
还…还不错嘛
It looks plausible.
看起来是个说得通的对手
Not at all!
完全不行
No redeeming qualities.
没有任何可取之处
I can't feel your intention at all.
我完全感觉不到你的心意
Even if you get changed, you still don't change your mind.
就算改变了服装 心意还是没改变
When she knows it's plausible, she suddenly becomes bold.
一知道说得通 就突然变大胆了
What a long face.
脸太长了
In this era, what we all crave is the healing given by the maid.
现在这个时代 大家渴求的是女仆给予的疗愈
Don't act like a cleric.
别摆出圣职人员的动作
The feeling of sincerely serving others
诚心诚意侍奉他人的心情
is more healing than any recovery magic.
比任何回复魔法 还有疗愈作用
It can be said to be the ultimate healing magic.
可以说是究极疗愈魔法
You can't heal just by dressing up as a maid.
只是穿上女仆装 是无法给予真正的疗愈
There's a healer who can't heal others.
也有人明明是僧侣 也无法疗愈他人
But...
可是…
It's really difficult for the resentful ghost to pursue healing.
怨灵想追求疗愈 难度真的很高
All right. I got it.
好 这样吧
This time, me "healing specialist" is shortened to "heal-cialist".
这次我这个"疗愈特别专家" 简称"疗特专家"
It's so hard to read.
太难念了
Let me teach you the true secret of healing.
来教教你疗愈真正的奥秘
Really?
真的吗
The training is very strict and hard. Can you do it?
训练非常严格辛苦 你办得到吗
OK.
OKK
So easy.
好随便
100 PUSH UPS, 200 SIT UPS
(俯卧撑 100次 腹筋 200次)
"VOICE PRACTICE TEN MINUTES, SQUAT TEN TIMES (TWO GROUPS)" Carla made a list of
(发声练习 10分钟 深蹲 10次 两组) 卡菈订出了超艰难的
"CARLA AMAZING 100 TIMES" extremely difficult special training.
(卡菈 超棒 100次) 特训清单
Although the list is made, it's not mandatory.
虽然清单列好了 但也不是非执行不可
Anyway, it's okay to smile.
总之 露出笑容就很OK
All right.
是
I don't know what she said for five minutes.
不知道说些什么说了五分钟
Then...
然后
It's done. Yeah.
完成了 耶
I don't think anything has changed... No. Is he a little twisted?
我觉得没什么变… 不 他是不是有点扭曲
Do it the way I taught you.
照我教你的方法去做吧
Have you taught it the way?
方法 你有教吗
Wel... Wel...
欢欢欢…
Welcome... Welcome...
欢迎欢迎…
-Ba... ba... ck... ck... -Is that all right? It seems a little bad.
-回回回回来来来来 -这没问题吧 好像有点糟
Meow.
喵
What?
屁啦
No. Hold up, hold up.
不不 等等等等
Who are you?
你谁啊
Who? What are you talking about?
什么谁啊 说什么呢
She's the resentful ghost.
她是怨灵啊
She has been here.
她刚才一直在这啊
No way.
哪有
"BEFORE AFTER" She was another creature just now.
(Befor After) 刚才她还是另一种生物啊
Oh, well. What creature?
讨厌 什么生物啦
She's already dead.
她已经死了
That's not the point!
吐槽的点不对吧
But I know why you're so surprised.
不过我懂你为什么这么惊讶
And I understand you want to compliment me.
也了解你想称赞我的心情
I'm glad you applauded me.
我很高兴你为我拍手喝采
But please calm down. Everyone, sit down.
但请冷静 大家先坐下
No one stands up and applauds, okay?
没人起立鼓掌好吗
One must purify the mind of the successor before inheriting the "healing mystery".
其实 让人继承"疗愈奥秘"前 必须先净化继承人的内心
Hold it. Then you don't inherit the mystery, do you?
慢着 那你应该没继承奥秘吧
Because your mind is very filthy.
因为你的内心十分污浊
The argument is pointless.
论点不攻自破
As a result, as you can see, the body and mind of the resentful ghost have been purified.
其结果如你所见 怨灵的身心都被净化了
Don't ignore me.
别无视啊
We didn't just talk.
刚才 我们也不是只有对话
By the way, let her express her dissatisfaction, pressure and troubles.
顺便让她发散平常的不满 压力还有烦恼等
A psychosomatic clinic?
身心科诊所吗
Therefore, the seeds of her anxiety and worry were carefully resolved by me.
因此她的不安与烦恼的种子 都被我仔细化解了
Doesn't this pose appear too often?
这个姿势是不是太频繁出现了
Yes, just like... Like a god of death who ends the lives of living people.
对 就像… 结束活人生命的死神那般
I'm sick of your words.
我受够你的用词了
Hang on a second.
等一下
You're alive. No, you're dead.
活过来了 啊不 你死了
Thank you for helping me just now.
刚才谢谢你帮助我
No!
不对啦
She becomes lovely after being purified...
她被净化之后就变得很可爱…
She's a ghost, but she's so lovely.
明明是幽灵还这么可爱
She has the same character as me.
完全就是跟我撞角了嘛
Why would you say that to the person who killed you?
你对杀了你的对象 说这种话好吗
Wait a minute!
给我等一下
I won't turn my status as the lovely mascot over to anyone.
我不会把可爱吉祥物的地位 让给任何人
Nobody thinks so, okay?
没人这么想好吗
Hold on. Speaking of lovely mascot...
等一下 说到可爱吉祥物…
Shut up!
闭嘴
Speaking of cute character...
说到可爱角色…
-Just shut up! -It must be me.
-你给我闭嘴 -…绝对是我
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW "THE SECOND PART OF "WHAT'S THIS STORY" MAKES ANNA AND RYOKO,"
(下集预告) ("这是什么故事"的第二篇)
"WHO AREN'T IN THE ORIGINAL WORK "DON'T HURT ME, MY HEALER"," That's great, Ryoko.
(让"这个僧侣有够烦"原著中) 太好了灵子
"ACTIVE IN THE ANIMATION. IT'S EXCITING." We made our debut in animation.
(没登场的安娜和灵子在动画中活跃 真的很令人高兴) 我们在动画里出道了
"THANK YOU FOR MAKING UP THE INSUFFICIENT PART OF THE ORIGINAL WORK IN THE ANIMATION." That's right.
(另外也很感谢动画补足了原著中交代不足的部分) 就是啊
"ON THE OTHER HAND, A POPULAR ANIMATION APPEARED IN THIS EPISODE." Anna.
(另一方面这集出现了某个国民人气动画哏) 安娜
"I BELIEVE EVERYONE UNDERSTANDS WITHOUT EXPLAINING IT." We're not even in business books.
(当然不必在此说明大家都懂) 我们都没出现在商业书刊里呢
"IN THOSE DAYS, INSTEAD OF USING A DIGITAL BRUSH," And since the next episode,
(但今非昔比当年可不是用数位画笔) 而且从下集开始
"REAL DRAWING TOOLS" we're fixed characters.
(而是用真正的绘图工具) 我们是固定角色
"WERE USED TO DRAW OUTLINES AND COLOUR." It's like a dream.
(一笔一笔绘出轮廓涂上颜色) 简直就像在做梦一样
"IT MAY BE GOOD TO LET PEOPLE KNOW" Let's work hard together.
(能借此让众人知道当年的工作人员为了动画) 我们一起加油
"THAT THE STAFF BACK THEN REALLY WORKED HARD AND" Heat up the show.
(真是燃烧热情费尽辛劳) 炒热节目吧
"HAD BEEN PASSIONATE ABOUT ANIMATION. THAT'S EPISODE 11." Only two episodes left.
(或许也算是一件好事的第十一话) 只剩下两集了
"STAY TUNED." Wh...
(要继续观看哦) 什…